Hello hello everyone how are you all I am
your own personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and
you are watching this real The credit for today's video goes to
Mr. Ravi ji Ravi ji
said in the comment that brother make a video
on that flame Thank you very much
for your comment and according to your comment today
we will talk about a film related to life insurance We will
know the details
Before moving ahead I request you that you
people want that according to your comment
videos keep coming on the channel then
you just have to like the video Like it does
not cost any money as you know
Now before that let us learn about death claim There are
some basic to important points
which you must know You must be knowing
why you should know If
you do not know if you make a mistake then
your claim will be rejected Like
if you have already taken a life insurance policy
or are going to take it then
you have to disclose even the smallest information in the form You have to
mention it
Nothing has to be hidden Abe what is it
Suppose like sir I am under  If I
understand you, then they already have this
life insurance policy, now
they have taken a life insurance product from another company
and did not tell about the one which is already insured,
now if it goes to theirs in future then in
such a case the insurance company
can definitely reject the claim, a similar
case had happened till the Supreme Court, when it went to the claim, the
claim was not received, keep this thing in mind,
therefore every small thing has to be
clearly mentioned in the form, the second
important thing is that your policy should be
in working condition, it is not that the grace
period has passed and you have
not paid the premium of the policy and in such a case if death occurs then that
claim will not be received until revival is done
and when you do revival, if the
graduate has passed and your two-three
months have also passed, then you will have to get revival done, in
such a situation you will have to mention your illness, your
condition, help conditions
properly, you will have to tell again,
if you hide anything then it can become
urgent for you later, now
you know how death cases happen, is it
natural or due to some disease  This is
due to an accident, so the first thing is that
if the death case is decided in any way, then
you do not have to wait for a long time,
you have to inform the insurance company
in writing as soon as possible, you have to inform them in writing.
Now if you do this then you can get the
benefit of the rules, like the
insurance company has to inform them within 15 days about the
documents
that they need and apart from this, if any
additional investigation has to be done then they have to
complete it within 180 days from the date
of the best, okay, from whichever side you
give intimation to the company, then I would say within
seven days, you should inform the company in any case,
now let's talk about natural death
or glass yasin, due to which
if there is a tooth, then
what document will be required because your original
board will be required, okay, policy bond, original
death certificate will be required, your ID proof will be required in
which there should be a life shot and a
photo of the person who is going to make the claim,
that ID proof will
require the complete record of medical treatment, discharge summary,
investigation report, doctor's
certificate etc. okay, yes and for this  Along with this, you will
also need the click where the question sanskar is written. Along with this, if you had
consulted a family doctor, then you will
also
need a certificate of his setting or a certificate from the medical
practitioner in the hospital.
If the employers or the places where you were working, they
put it at the time of the accident, then you will need their certificate from there
and along with this you will
also need a claim form, which you will get
from the branch,
you will get it on the official website, so these are the
documents which you will have to give, okay, now
suppose there is an accidental death, then all the
documents that I have just told you will be required, along with that,
like your post-mortem report, which should be
attested against the police officials, the
attested copy of the light FIR, the
original through the police officers, that will also be
required, if you had got any clipping out of the newspaper
etc., then
a photocopied copy of that newspaper cutting will also be required and
if there was hospitalization, complete from Ghuma.
Discharge summary, investigation report,
medical treatment, and
a certificate from the doctor. All the complete
documents will be required. Claim form
of any company which you possibly have. You have to
type the name of the company on Google and the
death claim form will appear in front of you.
Here we have taken the example of HDFC,
so you will find this link in the description,
click on it, the interface will come up
and see, they have given all the details
but even after that it is written that you
must visit the branch and when you apply for the claim process,
every company
gives you an acknowledgement letter, that is, they have given
you an intimation, the chief vintage
informs a policy holder
that it has processed your claim for them
or what documents are there, what are the
requirements, they tell there only. Now there is a small
advisor, suppose if the early death has happened
within three years of various policies, then
my advisor will be there. Take all the
documents you have,
go straight to the branch and don't get into the hassle of online.
Okay, now you can watch as many videos as you want
on YouTube.  You should also read this article to
set up an approved insurance company. If there is any, then do
not hesitate at all in contacting the insurance company. Things keep changing, the
rules of all the companies also change,
even small things
change in the claim form, so it does not happen that whatever is told to you today will be
relevant tomorrow. Keep this thing in
mind, whatever other documents are
told to you, the main lead document is required.